Caleb Scoville: Welcome welcome my name is caleb I am your trainer for today.
Caleb Scoville: Alexander have we done a training before have I done a training with you.
Caleb Scoville: All right, let me check.
Caleb Scoville: I don't know if you up.
Caleb Scoville: I thought that might be the case, I was like he's probably got something going on with his audio or something I totally get it.
Caleb Scoville: No worries at all i'm just going to check and see how many more people were expecting.
Caleb Scoville: which you know for a Friday to.
Caleb Scoville: That works.
Caleb Scoville: There we go.
Caleb Scoville: Oh Nice, how are you.
Alexander C. Eisner: How are you.
Caleb Scoville: that's good good.
Caleb Scoville: Have we done a training before Alex no okay.
Caleb Scoville: cool must have been another Alexander, then I guess.
Caleb Scoville: Where are you located where you at.
Alexander C. Eisner: i'm in seal beach where you.
Caleb Scoville: say that again.
Alexander C. Eisner: there'll beach California.
Caleb Scoville: Oh cool i'm in utah I grew up in Washington state but i'm been in utah for a while.
Oh cool.
Caleb Scoville: What part of California is.
Caleb Scoville: Is that.
Alexander C. Eisner: A seal beach is the northern most beach city of Orange county before you get to long beach, which is the southern much Bead city of La county.
Caleb Scoville: cool cool cool cool I knew I recognize that my dad grew up in in the garden grove Westminster area my grandfather was a judge in southern California, for years, but that was like.
Caleb Scoville: Probably 20 years ago when he retired so.
Alexander C. Eisner: garden grove and Westminster are right here.
Caleb Scoville: Okay cool yeah my my grandmother she lived about a half mile away from mile square park growing up, and so we would always run over there, played pickup basketball growing up.
Caleb Scoville: Let me check my.
Caleb Scoville: Calendar here let's take a look we're just going to get started in like 30 seconds, whether we have people or not, but.
Caleb Scoville: OK cool yep we can get started that's great and Hello hello to you lance welcome welcome as well.
Caleb Scoville: awesome Well, my name is caleb I am your trainer for today, I am a member of the training team, I do trainings for file vine Louis docket and a new.
Caleb Scoville: A new product that we just acquired new product and company that we just are called outlaw which is more like contracts signing of contracts.
Caleb Scoville: So i'm excited for everything, but hopefully before today you have taken the basics, training and not necessarily required.
Caleb Scoville: But really helpful if specially if you are like the main admin at your firm is the customs editor training where you're learning how to edit your build your project template, as it were, so that's a really good one to have and be able to use.
Caleb Scoville: let's.
Caleb Scoville: let's get out of this Okay, so now i'm going to come into a specific case.
Caleb Scoville: And that case.
Caleb Scoville: is going to help us understand what we need to know in order for this to work now if.
Caleb Scoville: You didn't know all the rules, but you kind of knew a little bit how to navigate you could probably get some of your templates done.
Caleb Scoville: But when it comes to templates that maybe are a little bit more complicated that involves bringing in fields.
Caleb Scoville: and information from fields, from a lot of different sections and putting them onto a document that's where this training really does shop fine.
Caleb Scoville: Because you have to know the rules in order for it to happen so basically Oh, and I didn't ask Alexander and lance what are your practice areas within your firm.
Alexander C. Eisner: i'm a personal injury attorney.
Caleb Scoville: personal injury awesome and then lance you can put it in the chat or unmute whatever works.
Lance Lugtu: Medical director my daughter efforts coordinate our.
Caleb Scoville: Medical emitter okay so you're kind of in this in the same realm is the personal injury as well.
Caleb Scoville: Yes, awesome okay that's great because the template example that I use in my trainings as a medical records request and it doesn't always work for every law.
Caleb Scoville: Practice area right but it's a really great example and helping us understand all of the rules so let's go to the activity section, so I can type out a couple things in order to understand the rules.
Caleb Scoville: on how we create the stock generations.
Caleb Scoville: You have to understand how these sections work here on the left.
Caleb Scoville: we've got three of them they're built in sections, there are custom static section in our custom collection sections okay built ins.
Caleb Scoville: As you can probably imagine, these are the ones that file vine has built out for you and you just kind of plug in and play we're talking specifically about like the calendar we're looking at the team section we're looking at.
Caleb Scoville: Our the docs section is a built in section, the yield calculator is a built in section, etc, so those are what built ins, are you just put them in there they're ready to go and you don't have to put in all of them.
Caleb Scoville: The activity section, which is where we're at right now is a built in section, but that's the only required section, and if you didn't learn that and customs editor I just told you and we're good.
Caleb Scoville: static.
Caleb Scoville: static is a type of custom section, so we get a we get a form pretty much, and we can populate it with all the different fields, a really great example of that is the intake right we put all of these questions, all of these places where we're filling out information it's a big old form.
Caleb Scoville: The thing about static, is that we don't really need to duplicate that information right we don't need to incident dates to intake dates to summary of information fields, for example, we just need one.
Caleb Scoville: In contrast, we have collection sections right, so the medical provider section right here that i've named meds renamed as meds.
Caleb Scoville: How many providers are we going to need on any given case well at least one right.
Caleb Scoville: Possibly 3141 51 who knows, and so we need to be able to duplicate that information as many times as we need, we need to be able to duplicate fields.
Caleb Scoville: provider name provider address all of these things so knowing what those sections are prepares us for knowing the rules and the rules dictate what we can and cannot do when we're creating these Doc gym forms.
Caleb Scoville: So now i'm going to come over to this Google Doc that i've created that doubles as both instructions and the template that we are going to create.
Caleb Scoville: So before we talk about that.
Caleb Scoville: The big thing here.
Caleb Scoville: Is that eventually we're going to use the customs editor to create a button sometimes referred to as a widget depending on where we place that button, whether we put it into a static section or a collection section or whatever.
Caleb Scoville: That determines and dictates what we can and cannot get to put on our template on our forum.
Caleb Scoville: If that didn't make sense, please let me know at any point you guys can unmute throw something in the chat whatever and i'm happy to repeat give some examples go back over something, let me know.
Caleb Scoville: So now.
Caleb Scoville: depending on where we put this button depends on what we get depends on what we have access to so let's say that we put our button.
Caleb Scoville: In a static section, or in other words we're going to have a button in the intake section, for example, we're going to click that button and hopefully we're going to get some kind of form that is pre filled because we connected it.
Caleb Scoville: To all of the other areas right that's awesome, but we can only get specific information if we place our button in a static section, and this is how it works.
Caleb Scoville: If we place our widget in a static section, then we get static data, or in other words data from static sections and it can be any static section.
Caleb Scoville: So if I put my button and take that I can get information from the intake and from the case summary.
Caleb Scoville: But my restriction here is that I cannot get any collection section data, and I might not need to when we're talking about like.
Caleb Scoville: A like an agreement or a welcome letter or something like that you probably don't need anything from a collection section, you might, which is why we're.
Caleb Scoville: Doing this training to help you understand what you can and can't get but um but that's what we're going to do that's what we're going to determine.
Caleb Scoville: If we place our widget if we place our button in a collection section, for example, meds liens expenses.
Caleb Scoville: Then I can get collection section data in that same section.
Caleb Scoville: But only from that same section I can't get information from meds and from liens.
Caleb Scoville: I can only get it from wherever I placed that button.
Caleb Scoville: And that's going to be a little bit clearer in just a minute when we're talking about the form that we're going to use.
Caleb Scoville: The rule summary here is that we can't use more than one collection section in adoption.
Caleb Scoville: But we can use as many static, as we want no matter what, and then, if we combine it with a collection section, we have to put our button in that collection section, and we are restricted to that collection section data.
Caleb Scoville: Now side note.
Caleb Scoville: let's say that you're looking at this and you're like wait.
Caleb Scoville: I was hoping to eventually have a settlement disbursement sheet I want a settlement disbursements sheet that has the total of the settlement amount, I want to be able to break it down based on meds expenses regular expenses liens.
Caleb Scoville: And anything else that I want, we cannot do that with Doc Jen what we're learning today we can't do that.
Caleb Scoville: But there's another tool called report fusion take note of that, if this is something interesting is that this is something that you're interested in and that's a separate training that you would do.
Caleb Scoville: All right.
Caleb Scoville: Now let's look at our steps, these are not steps that you have to follow every time.
Caleb Scoville: This is more of like guidelines to help you get to a good place and then, once you figure things out and you're doing good you're going to do it your own way, to a certain degree, there are certain things that you do have to do well take a look at those.
Caleb Scoville: Things like that you don't necessarily have to follow this format.
Caleb Scoville: But we are going to do that today.
Caleb Scoville: I also forgot to tell you that I am recording this we record all of our webinars and then i'll send out an email to you all a little bit later today.
Caleb Scoville: With that, with that recording.
Caleb Scoville: Step one choose the document that we want to convert into adoption template what do I want to do, I want to do a medical records request.
Caleb Scoville: And this is it don't laugh all right.
Caleb Scoville: Just a really simple medical records request I made it really simple, so that we could focus more on the process and the rules and everything, rather than the actual documents itself so anyways super simple authorizing the law firm whatever whatever.
Caleb Scoville: we'll come back to the highlighting and the colors in just a second now we're going to identify the text or strings of text that need to be changed, each time a new document is created right how many medical records request, are we going to do on one case.
Caleb Scoville: Quite a few right how many medical requests are we going to do.
Caleb Scoville: Firm wide tons tons and tons and tons of medical records request right, and so, depending on what case what provider, we are going to need.
Caleb Scoville: different pieces of information to change every time, sometimes on if we're on the same case certain pieces of information won't change.
Caleb Scoville: Such as maybe a paralegal or an attorney's name or something like that anyways.
Caleb Scoville: So let's come down I have highlighted again don't worry about the different colors just worry about the highlighting right now I want the date to change every time well I want the date to change when it's a new date for that date right, I want to current date in this date field.
Caleb Scoville: i'm going to need provider information provider name.
Caleb Scoville: Address information and i'm going to need treatment dates as well client information yeah i'm going to need the clients full name and i'm going to need paralegal and attorney information okay awesome.
Caleb Scoville: So I highlighted those that's what's going to change again, this is a part where you don't necessarily have to do this, you don't have to highlight these sections, this is just to give you an idea as to what needs to change.
Caleb Scoville: And the same thing with step three now we're going to identify in what sections, the corresponding fields are located.
Caleb Scoville: So, for example, I come down here and I see today's date where's that located well it's an especial field and it's like a dynamic code if that makes sense and an automatically generated dynamic code.
Caleb Scoville: it's a file vine specific code and i'm going to show you where to find it and what it looks like but that's what the red means is that it's that fine line specific code.
Caleb Scoville: orange i'm using orange to help me understand which of these of all the sections are men and men's information provider treatment dates great.
Caleb Scoville: Now, what type of section, are we dealing with here we're dealing with a collection section that should be a flag, not necessarily like a red flag or anything just a just a flag to be like Oh, this is good to pay attention to right based on those rules that we went over.
Caleb Scoville: client information okay client full name that's it where's that, coming from a static section specifically the client card is a static section K summary.
Caleb Scoville: Which is a static section we're doing paralegal and attorney great so now, this is where i'm going to turn it on you guys.
Caleb Scoville: And if you don't know that's fine sometimes the explanation doesn't do as much as actually like going through the process right but based on the rules that we talked about.
Caleb Scoville: Where we have to place our button, in order to get certain things and follow the rules here where for for this medical records request, where do we need to place our button, where do we need to place our widget and what section.
Caleb Scoville: Take a wild guess make it make it real wild.
Caleb Scoville: Exactly exactly Alexander yes.
Caleb Scoville: If we put the button for our medical records request in the client section or in the case summary.
Caleb Scoville: We will only be able to get static data, we will, we will not be able to get meds information medical provider information, it has to go in this collection section and from there, I can get the meds info and static information as well.
Caleb Scoville: If I had like some cool file line swag and send it your way Alexander, but I don't but i'm asking for them to give me stuff to handout for questions like that.
Caleb Scoville: that's true all right five five, but you can have it.
Caleb Scoville: All right.
Caleb Scoville: So.
Caleb Scoville: Okay, so that's what we just did based on these things where we're going to put it.
Caleb Scoville: Up we're going to put it into our meds section using the customs editor tool we're going to create a widget so i'm going to come over to my far left here.
Caleb Scoville: And i've already got my advanced section up and that's because I was doing a training and the advanced section before, but where we want to go main menu down to advanced and then that will put us.
Caleb Scoville: into okay stop that there we go customs editor that's where I want to go again hopefully you've done this.
Caleb Scoville: If not, I know that some firms will send individuals to do this, training, not having done the customs editor because you're not like a main admin anyways choose our org if we've got multiple.
Caleb Scoville: We are going to choose the project type, which in this case is personal injury.
Caleb Scoville: And now we've got our project tech we've got our built, we are going to put a widget into one of these sections here so we're in our sections.
Caleb Scoville: are going to come down meds this is where I want my button to go.
Caleb Scoville: So I am going.
Caleb Scoville: To click on that come down to where it says custom fields widgets and I can feel my computer slowing down a little bit I apologize.
Caleb Scoville: But us add a field slash widget this is going to be a widget.
Caleb Scoville: widget type.
Caleb Scoville: Doc generation.
Caleb Scoville: Doc generation multi template Doc generation is just a single button.
Caleb Scoville: Sick well sorry Doc generation is a button, with a single template inside of it, so if we're like a cool medical records request we're not going to need anything else.
Caleb Scoville: In this button it's just going to need to be one.
Caleb Scoville: Great you can set up adoption.
Caleb Scoville: By itself if there's a chance you might need more than one or if you know that there's more than one that you want to put into a single button.
Caleb Scoville: And you can choose Doc generation multi template and what that does is you click inside of it.
Caleb Scoville: And it gives you a little drop down of all of your templates to choose from, so it is it functions exactly the same as Doc Jen the single dose now.
Caleb Scoville: i'm going to assume that you know something about hashtags all of you within file vine we use hashtags as a assigned searchable keyword.
Caleb Scoville: On an object in this case, we can set up an automatic posh hashtag.
Caleb Scoville: To say all right, every time I create a new document from this doctrine widget it's going to automatically get a hashtag, for example, I could put in.
Caleb Scoville: hashtag m ar ar.
Caleb Scoville: So now, every time I click on a button to generate the template that's associated with this button it's going to automatically get this hashtag.
Caleb Scoville: hey that's great unless you put a bunch of different templates that aren't really related and then they would get a hashtag that isn't really related that makes sense, so that's we got going on let's name this widget real quick and we're going to say.
Caleb Scoville: For.
Caleb Scoville: Medical.
Caleb Scoville: records requests.
Caleb Scoville: i'm just going to shorten up.
Caleb Scoville: awesome.
Caleb Scoville: So we can do that hashtag great auto move to folder do we want it to automatically be linked into a specific folder rather than just the general.
Caleb Scoville: Doc docs area yeah that sounds nice so let's go ahead and move to a folder.
Caleb Scoville: So now i've got a little folder in here called medicals.
Caleb Scoville: And i've got sub folders records and requests, so I will say yeah when link that in to the request folder.
Caleb Scoville: Alright, so let's go and create that pretty simple.
Caleb Scoville: phone all right now we can come over here to the left and click on Doc generation setup.
Caleb Scoville: Now we're going to find the widget so the widget itself in this case is almost like a little house and we are going to create a template and we're going to put it inside of this House kind of like.
Caleb Scoville: I guess you could say it was kind of like furniture we're dressing dressing, the House fitting the House.
Caleb Scoville: So we've created the little house let's find it.
Caleb Scoville: And let's see what's on the inside.
Caleb Scoville: Project type greats in the midsection.
Caleb Scoville: And here's one that we just created for medical are.
Caleb Scoville: Great Okay, so now, if we want this to work, we need to get a template in here but currently we don't we have a template but we don't have specific codes inside of this template so let's go ahead and click on field list.
Caleb Scoville: field list gives me all of my fields that I have access to with corresponding codes so basically i'm going to put today long on my template and now, when I run it through that widget when I click on that button it's going to give me today's date every single time.
Caleb Scoville: So what i'm going to do right now.
Caleb Scoville: i've got two screens here, but I.
Caleb Scoville: can't really use both of them for zoom so.
Caleb Scoville: I am going to take my document.
Caleb Scoville: and put it, side by side.
Caleb Scoville: With my codes.
Caleb Scoville: So now basically it's a matter of finding the right code and moving that code over here to the right hand side so let's look at our rules real quick.
Caleb Scoville: Customs editor create a widget reduction look at the widget open the field list seven transfer the field codes from the field list to the template okay so that's field codes in the field list is the one on the Left template is the one in here on the right.
Caleb Scoville: Okay.
Caleb Scoville: Wonderful file line specific code great it's here at the top we're not going to make you dig for this random code that you may not know about so march 4 2022 great like that's the format that I want so it's going to be this today long.
Caleb Scoville: You could.
Caleb Scoville: highlight this code copy and paste it don't do that okay click on this little clipboard right here.
Caleb Scoville: Once it flashes green That means that it has been copied to your clipboard with everything on here.
Caleb Scoville: Copying and pasting manually means that you could leave off one of these curly braces on each end if you do that, it will not let you even upload the template because it's not a valid code without all of those curly braces.
Caleb Scoville: Now i'm going to come over here and, as you can probably imagine.
Caleb Scoville: i'm just going to paste that in there.
Caleb Scoville: Now, and at the end i'm going to take off all of my highlighting.
Caleb Scoville: Because I don't need the highlighting and the highlighting will carry over into the template itself so i'll remove all of that, at the same time.
Caleb Scoville: All right, provider information that's going to be in my midsection so let's talk about how we can get to this information.
Caleb Scoville: Well, a couple things that we can do.
Caleb Scoville: Is we can take a look at this meds section right here, but this is a long section, there are so many fields in here we're still on meds still on meds we are still on meds and i've been scrolling for a day and a half just.
Caleb Scoville: So we could go ahead and scroll through and make sure we find everything but look there's a method to the madness, just like with any code right meds dot whatever so we're talking about the meds section.
Caleb Scoville: we're talking about the field that's in the midsection So if I were to do.
Caleb Scoville: let's go ahead and do my command F i'm on a MAC so command F for you for those PC users you've got your control F right.
Caleb Scoville: And then i'm going to put in mets okay meds.so now i've got all these in here.
Caleb Scoville: Where are we going to get this provider information that we need well let's go ahead and come to the case.
Caleb Scoville: A little different view, because it is.
Caleb Scoville: minimized.
Caleb Scoville: we're come to this midsection because this is where the fields are that I want.
Caleb Scoville: Now inside of the midsection.
Caleb Scoville: i've got my collections my collection item of all of my medical providers that i've that i've got inside of each one of these providers, we have the same exact fields.
Caleb Scoville: Not the same information, but the same fields, the same boxes and everything like that let's go ahead and click on the medical offices of Jenny our Peters we're going to find out what the field is.
Caleb Scoville: Where this information that we want to get where what it's what it's called.
Caleb Scoville: So i've got this information up here, which is nice but there isn't really a field up here, but if I come down, something that you're going to see as soon as this finishes loading.
Caleb Scoville: i've got a.
Caleb Scoville: field called provider.
Caleb Scoville: Now provider is what we call a contact field.
Caleb Scoville: Which means that we've got a field called provider.
Caleb Scoville: But inside of that field called provider we've got a lot of other fields fields within a field within a section it's kind of like file vine inception going on here.
Caleb Scoville: So.
Caleb Scoville: Oh, there we go there, we go, are you still hasn't populated So while we wait for that let's go back to our codes so let's go ahead and start typing in.
Caleb Scoville: provider.
Caleb Scoville: As you can see we've got that setup MED stop provider Doc and then here are my fields within this field.
Caleb Scoville: Now, again, you don't have to do it like this i'm helping you understand how the fields work how the codes work and how you could find certain things okay so within provider.
Caleb Scoville: zip contact card hopefully you've seen one of these open.
Caleb Scoville: But basically it's contact card it's got a bunch of information in it and the information is based on these fields that are inside.
Caleb Scoville: um.
Caleb Scoville: Okay, so that's great.
Caleb Scoville: In the future, like by future I mean like three minutes or less, we are going to be interested in the name of the provider so but really what we want now is the address and the name of the provider, which is its own code and we're going to take a look at that.
Caleb Scoville: So, if we take a look we've got address one block with company info.
Caleb Scoville: ooh regardless oh good question um.
Caleb Scoville: So there are there are ways to do things like that.
Caleb Scoville: Like if if they're male than us his if they're female use her, so there are those types of things that we do we don't cover that in this training, specifically, there are ways to do.
Caleb Scoville: Something like that, so I can't necessarily say in good conscious conscience that we can definitely do that, I would say what would it be called.
Caleb Scoville: contingent I, I think that they're called.
Caleb Scoville: Oh there's a name for it and I can't remember and that's because, as our as trainers we don't really do that because it's not within our scope of training.
Caleb Scoville: But um, but if you asked technical support or whoever your REP is through file vine and you said something like had a doctrine, this is the question that I asked he's yep yep bullion or conditional logic is a is a good way is a good way to describe it yep.
Caleb Scoville: yeah Thank you Alexandra.
Caleb Scoville: All right.
Caleb Scoville: yeah you're welcome great question yeah there is a boolean section at the bottom of the page as well um when it comes to.
Caleb Scoville: yeah let's take it, we can take a look at that as well, actually real quick before we navigate away let's grab this address one with block with company info grab it let's place it right in here.
Caleb Scoville: Will paste it in awesome yeah there's a section down here.
Caleb Scoville: With a lot of like little like, for example, if you had a social security number and you wanted to display only the last four digits but the field itself has all.
Caleb Scoville: However, many tickets are into nine is at nine digits first social security number.
Caleb Scoville: yeah so there's really cool little tips and tricks and we don't I mean they are really awesome we just don't have time to cover.
Caleb Scoville: them in this training necessarily but yeah you've got some of these conditions, yes, no it's true, though this if not So these are some these are some good resources.
Caleb Scoville: um i'm not exactly sure if this will give you what you want, but this is a good, it is a good starter Thank you Alexandra for pointing that out.
Caleb Scoville: yeah there's different capitalization ones as well, this is the one that I was talking about string field Mon fires.
Caleb Scoville: All right.
Caleb Scoville: Let us.
Caleb Scoville: This is so there are so many codes here, which is part of the reason why i'm i'm probably giving you more information than you want possibly that you need a part of that is so that you don't get lost necessarily in this huge list of all of these codes.
Caleb Scoville: Because I love you because I love you very much, all right let's find the provider name.
Caleb Scoville: Now, remember how we have a field called name well that's pretty easy, we can just put in name.
Caleb Scoville: awesome notice, also on the Left we've got these field names these field names correspond with the fields themselves sometimes they get a little bit tricky so we're going to look at when would be good, and when would not, in this case.
Caleb Scoville: The field itself doesn't say provider full name it just says name so that's where this can come in handy but it's going copy that.
Caleb Scoville: let's pop that in.
Caleb Scoville: awesome okay let's skip clients name for now because let's just do the treatment dates, this is one of those times.
Caleb Scoville: When having.
Caleb Scoville: When when doing a general search can be beneficial, because how many fields are we going to have that have the word treatment inside of them not.
Caleb Scoville: Nearly not a fraction of how many fields are going to have the word name or client inside of them, so we can actually just go and type in treatment.
Caleb Scoville: we've got 16 results, we can double check this great meds dot true meds dot date treatment completed great day treatment started great where are we getting that information from.
Caleb Scoville: In each one of these providers we've got a field called date treatment started bone date trip and completed bum and we can copy these.
Caleb Scoville: field names and put it into our search here and get because that's it again won't always be the case, but in a lot of these will be so date treatment started great let's grab that.
Caleb Scoville: paste that in.
Caleb Scoville: You do this and Ricardo get to your question and shut the second.
Caleb Scoville: pasted this one when searching in those fields is there buttons that tell you where that field is oh like if you were to find the field here and then want to know exactly where it's at.
Caleb Scoville: So you're saying yeah so the closest that this will get you is the fact that this says meds you're going to know that this field is in the midsection.
Caleb Scoville: that's about it, you could once you say okay meds i'm looking for date treatment completed in the midsection well, you can come into the midsection you can open up one of your providers and then you can do search for.
Caleb Scoville: treatments treatment there are seven of those and then you can kind of filter through but there it is so that's probably the best work around that I have for you there isn't really like a.
Caleb Scoville: Like a way to like click on anything in it, for it to take you for for it to give you an explanation as to where it is but that's not a bad idea.
Caleb Scoville: Great question yeah Of course I like your questions guys and your help in answering some of these questions as well.
Caleb Scoville: Alright treatment client client, this is a little dangerous because i'm going to just type in client, but it turns out that the majority of these client fields.
Caleb Scoville: Have client as part of the code or as part of the field itself, and so, if I can move through a couple of these that don't really matter like client payments and use my little down carrot right up here.
Caleb Scoville: Then I can get to my client section So these are all of my client fields okay um if we're wanting the clients full name, then we've got a client full name client dot name is our code let's go ahead and.
Caleb Scoville: copy that bring it over alright so same thing with my case summary, the name of the section is called case summary so i'm going to.
Caleb Scoville: put that in there now Why am I not looking just for a straight for paralegal or more, or even more so for just doing an attorney search well that's because I happen to have several fields and several of these sections with attorney and with attorney contact cards as well, so long.
Caleb Scoville: We could talk about it later, but.
Caleb Scoville: anyways so with a summary i'm looking for a specific.
Caleb Scoville: area and we're gonna we're going to just type in paralegal because I know, in the case summary that field with para para legal information is called paralegal and that's what I need so paralegal dot the first thing that I need his name.
Caleb Scoville: And there it is.
Caleb Scoville: There we go.
Caleb Scoville: Is that in we do want to be careful as we're putting these in to make sure that the commas, and the periods go right up against.
Caleb Scoville: That last curly brace that last curly bracket and they do need to be there, I mean if you want them there, they need to be there i'm also if you have.
Caleb Scoville: A like a word and a code that come up and our kind of touching each other, like, for example on and MED state treatment started it's going to have the word on and a date that's right up connected to it, so we ought to make sure that those spacing that spacing as correct as well.
Caleb Scoville: All right, we need an email.
Caleb Scoville: If you're if you're wondering like I have wondered.
Caleb Scoville: Why are there so many fields like there are so many fields that are in here it's because well part of it has to do with these contact cards because within each contact card, there are fields.
Caleb Scoville: And within each one of these fields, there is the ability to have more than one in many cases, so, for example with with email, you can have up to eight emails in a contact card and they're all here.
Caleb Scoville: So let's grab the first one, so I know that my paralegals just have one.
Caleb Scoville: And i'm just making sure to grab that right there perfect okay attorney.
Caleb Scoville: attorneys work works, a little bit well it's going to work a little bit different because it's not just attorney in the section, as the field name its primary.
Caleb Scoville: attorney.
Caleb Scoville: So if I were to put in case summary dot attorney I wouldn't get anything has to be dot whatever the exact name of the field is so anyways premier turning great I just want the name.
Caleb Scoville: pop it in grab that.
Caleb Scoville: And will actually take this because we're done with codes.
Caleb Scoville: we're going to put this in there, I did this a little different the font font size, the building, because I want you to see that if you change that.
Caleb Scoville: If if you want it to be a different font than the rest, if you want it to be bolted, and everything like that, whatever you do to that code.
Caleb Scoville: Is what the actual text will show up when we generate as well right, which is why i'm going to get rid of.
Caleb Scoville: All of my highlighting.
Caleb Scoville: awesome double check on their great great great periods comma but i'm OK, and now i'm going to get rid of everything else up here.
Caleb Scoville: But before I do that we're going to make sure that it's in dot exe file format, so if you're using Google docs you just download it as a word document it's automatically Doc X.
Caleb Scoville: If you're working in Microsoft word, you need to make sure that when you're saving it it's an exe file format, which is the most recent file format okay.
Caleb Scoville: Sometimes formatting changes Is it better to do PDF um it depends on the form it depends on what you're going for I know that there are some law firms who take the PDF off of the Court website and then they use that because it's already made for them the PDF is, but you can do um.
Caleb Scoville: You can do these similar things in PDF.
Caleb Scoville: PDF doesn't look as nice when we're looking at like letters and, in this case of medical records request.
Caleb Scoville: But PDF takes on a couple additional steps, which is that with a PDF we would make a blank PDF first and then we would enter in Philadelphia fields if you're familiar with how to do that.
Caleb Scoville: And then you'd save it you import it without codes and then inside of file vine you're going to pop your codes in there and we can go over that i'm could go over that in a little bit depending on time as well yeah great question.
Caleb Scoville: Great question.
Caleb Scoville: Okay.
Caleb Scoville: And then we're going to upload it into the widget great and then we're going to go activate that button and get what we've been waiting for.
Caleb Scoville: awesome is our template that works.
Caleb Scoville: download it.
Caleb Scoville: Because we're in Google box I just worked in Google box a lot and have for pretty much my whole all of my careers so let's go ahead and file.
Caleb Scoville: download.
Caleb Scoville: Microsoft word.
Caleb Scoville: Great so as that's downloading let's come over here.
Caleb Scoville: Open this backup will leave our codes, why not we're going to come back to the inside of our widget.
Caleb Scoville: Great so now we're going to upload that template.
Caleb Scoville: And that's basically it we're uploading the template then we're going to go click the button now if you get some kind of error.
Caleb Scoville: On your end when you're uploading then there's something going on with your codes you're missing a curly bracket maybe you tried to modify.
Caleb Scoville: The code.
Caleb Scoville: and put something in there, that was like custom it's not gonna work, I tried it.
Caleb Scoville: was a while back, but I gave I gave it a shot, you know.
Caleb Scoville: Alright Doc generation templates great we've got that in there, the disappeared momentarily.
Caleb Scoville: over here on the right, we can download this we can preview it, we can edit it, we can replace we can trash it and we can also add in other templates as well.
Caleb Scoville: This That being said, this is the new home for this template really if you couldn't find the original one that was through word or through Google docs or something like that, or maybe you just deleted it.
Caleb Scoville: for whatever reason, it will always be here, this is like a little folder for all of the doctrines associated with this widget.
Caleb Scoville: So let's go back to our case.
Caleb Scoville: let's refresh.
Caleb Scoville: yeah whenever i'm using file vine and sharing my screen zoom zoom by itself takes up a lot of bandwidth right, but especially if you're sharing your screen it's.
Caleb Scoville: kind of ridiculous.
Caleb Scoville: And the reason why i'm refreshing.
Caleb Scoville: Is because many times with, especially with Doc Jen.
Caleb Scoville: If you have a case open that you've been using along this process.
Caleb Scoville: um.
Caleb Scoville: It won't it won't auto refresh those sections it auto refreshes the.
Caleb Scoville: Activity feed, but it won't auto refresh documents it won't auto refresh.
Caleb Scoville: Different custom sections on the left.
Caleb Scoville: I don't think it auto refreshes anything except for the activity feed.
Caleb Scoville: record low, can you change the type of field.
Caleb Scoville: Where the Doc goes if it was previous at previously set to one template.
Caleb Scoville: And only lets your place and not add without replacing the whole thing.
Caleb Scoville: i'm not sure I completely understand that question, but let me give us give a give it a stab So it goes into.
Caleb Scoville: Oh, a.
Caleb Scoville: Yes, so like if you are in.
Caleb Scoville: If you are in a button, if you were in a widget that doesn't have this Plus, then it would only allow you to replace.
Caleb Scoville: you'd use like this would be this would be gone and you'd have to use this little up arrow to replace it.
Caleb Scoville: The only way would be to create a new widget so you can't convert you can't convert a widget that's just one.
Caleb Scoville: into into a multiple one yeah so you'd have to you would have to create the new one, I see okay i'm understanding that yeah you're welcome great question.
Caleb Scoville: um Alexander, is there a way to tell if some formatting requests like if you wanted something to stay on one line, for example, if a name were too long, it would make the font size smaller to keep it all in one line Oh, that is a good question.
Caleb Scoville: I don't think i've ever had that question as far as like keeping things, or like expanding size or retracting.
Caleb Scoville: And I can't even say like.
Caleb Scoville: I think there would be or there should be, because I don't I don't really even know I can't even say I don't think that there would because I don't know um Could we ask.
Caleb Scoville: And same thing with Ricardo question probably I would probably reach out to technical support I don't think that they know the answer either they could but they would probably know who to go to I have someone in mind, but they are.
Caleb Scoville: There they're like.
Caleb Scoville: Pretty high up and I don't really ask them for things anymore, because they're crazy busy.
Caleb Scoville: yeah that's a great question.
Caleb Scoville: I don't think that there is a way um I don't know I don't i'm not going to say one way or the other great question.
Caleb Scoville: it's been a long time since I found a group, like you, guys, who have had like good questions.
Caleb Scoville: I feel like for the last two months i've had some.
Caleb Scoville: i've had some very nice ladies who are very confused at the end alright so let's go in, here we can we can choose any of these so maybe some of you have wondered well how are we going to decipher between which provider, we want on that letter well the way that it works.
Caleb Scoville: In file line is it puts a button that puts a widget the same widget in every single one of these sections, so if I were to go into.
Caleb Scoville: American for regional hospital open that up scroll down to the very bottom my which is going to be there same thing with medical offices of ginny are Peters going to open that up and then i'm going to scroll all the way down to the bottom.
Caleb Scoville: Past my graveyard of.
Caleb Scoville: doctrine which it's past.
Caleb Scoville: Thanks this part takes a minute to so like all of these are doctrine that i've created for trainings but we wanted at the very bottom so we're going to scroll down and we're just going to wait for a minute.
Caleb Scoville: What other questions do you have while we wait, I mean it could be literally like a minute or two before we.
Caleb Scoville: For these widgets show up.
Caleb Scoville: Oh up here you're talking about Ricardo.
Caleb Scoville: Section yeah so the only.
Caleb Scoville: So there's a few different ways to to do this, so the so.
Caleb Scoville: sarah's contact card, which is either clicking on her picture her initials if there's no picture or on her name that's exactly what we looked at before, which was the client information.
Caleb Scoville: This is the project name, so it probably has its own field but I I don't think that its associated with the.
Caleb Scoville: With the client these vitals okay good so yeah let's talk about that these vitals are mirrored there are mirrored fields, from.
Caleb Scoville: The intake and the case summer and things like that, so I to answer your question where would we go to get the actual settlement amount.
Caleb Scoville: In a lot of firms that I work with it's in the case summary, but really it is determined by your firm, because if you create I can create a field called clients favorite ice cream.
Caleb Scoville: And I can put that into the intake and then, when I create adoption, I can find the.
Caleb Scoville: code for clients favorite ice cream put it on to my document and then it's going to show the client favorite ice cream on whatever that is.
Caleb Scoville: But I don't have to put it in intake I can put it in a summary get the same result, except that it's in a different section, so I so that first part case summary dot whatever and take dot whatever that's going to be what i'm looking at yeah great question alright.
Caleb Scoville: So coming on down.
Caleb Scoville: So this is what this is what the single button looks like.
Caleb Scoville: Medical request for provider great I can click on that generated when it's a multi template when I click inside.
Caleb Scoville: And it'll give me a little drop down.
Caleb Scoville: When it does that if I click on this.
Caleb Scoville: Then it's also going to give me like you see up here with these little eyes this I tells me this is the.
Caleb Scoville: hashtag, and this is where it's going to go into what folder so that's Nice because I don't play the guessing game.
Caleb Scoville: let's go ahead and generate this now.
Caleb Scoville: If it's a big document with a lot of fields.
Caleb Scoville: Sometimes it can take a minute for that to come through and by a minute I mean.
Caleb Scoville: Like a few minutes for that to generate.
Caleb Scoville: there's other factors such as Internet connection.
Caleb Scoville: Whether using zoom or not.
Caleb Scoville: This.
Caleb Scoville: I am not quite sure this is abnormal for this to happen on the size of template.
Caleb Scoville: And we may just need to refresh it but as soon we can refresh it and take a look in a second, but as soon as it populates we're going to get a word document right here we're going to be able to drop this down and do whatever we want with this document, as if it were in the Doc section.
Caleb Scoville: And, although it is displayed here, it will also appear in the Doc section wherever I directed it to go.
Caleb Scoville: So we are now going to refresh because I think it's in a loop.
Caleb Scoville: And that's and that's it, then we can download it, we can we could fax it if we are using fax through file vine.
Caleb Scoville: If we're using vine sign for sending out for like an electronic signature, we could do that straight from their bone make it happen, no downloading know uploading.
Caleb Scoville: And I think that's it, so I mean if you if you need to hop if you need to hop off, you can i'll show you, once this is done loading i'll show you the example.
Caleb Scoville: That is, that is, the training Ricardo does vine sign support texts like does like can we send a vine sign contract signature E signature out via text message.
Caleb Scoville: And then sign on a phone.
Caleb Scoville: Get notification to text to link yep yep so it'll do it'll do both email and text message at the same time as long as there's an email and a text texting specific number that's in there and it'll provide a link in both and then.
Caleb Scoville: nope part of that's part of the deal that's well to the best of my knowledge, because I actually don't do anything with product pricing.
Caleb Scoville: I know a little bit here and there, but my understanding is that both text messaging and email is just part of the standard package, there are some add ons like if you wanted to do like bulk sending but, for example, you work in mass tort and you're wanting to send out a.
Caleb Scoville: contract and agreement to everybody, then there, there are some additional costs there but, but that should be should be part of the basic plan, the basic product.
Caleb Scoville: you're very welcome my pleasure.
Caleb Scoville: My pleasure, I love vine sign.
Caleb Scoville: So there we go.
Caleb Scoville: You know what that's a good question I have gotten that question before I have not used docusign extensively i've used docusign for like.
Caleb Scoville: People sending it to me to sign i've created a couple docu signs, but it was a while it was a while back my yeah sure sign adobe sign Doc you sign and vine sign.
Caleb Scoville: um.
Caleb Scoville: My opinion from what i've experienced and, from what I have heard from.
Caleb Scoville: Relatively unbiased third parties like firms that transition from docusign divine sign is it's just really nice to have it internal from within file vine right and as far as most of the things that you are going to want to do.
Caleb Scoville: They work very similarly now Doc docusign does have some additional bells and whistles just like adobe acrobat has lots of bells and whistles that our internal PDF editor does not have.
Caleb Scoville: Yes, yep.
Caleb Scoville: Yes.
Caleb Scoville: yeah so whatever whatever you have created and put into that vine sign up and you put the fields in there, you can send it to anyone, you can put in a name.
Caleb Scoville: Of a contact find that contact and make it easier on yourself, but you can manually enter the name the email and the phone number, and it does not have to be file vine related.
Caleb Scoville: yep.
Caleb Scoville: All right, let's take a look here it is generated.
Caleb Scoville: If that happens, you just got to refresh and it will it will 99.9% of the time it will have generated and you'll be able to find it like I just did I clicked on it taking a look at this.
Caleb Scoville: At this.
Caleb Scoville: preview there we go.
Caleb Scoville: end of day Friday my brain is a little fried.
Caleb Scoville: So we're looking for a current date we're looking for provider specific information we're looking for paralegal clients attorney information as well.
Caleb Scoville: awesome there it is.
Caleb Scoville: there's my current date awesome got the.
Caleb Scoville: provider information we've got the client we've got the treatment dates paralegal and attorney information and then from here i've got some options, I can.
Caleb Scoville: print it appear next to it, I can connect this to Microsoft word and Edit it without having to download it maybe there's some extra information an extra sentence that I want to type whatever.
Caleb Scoville: This I don't know if you guys learned about this yet it's called edit in place and basically we have filed line as a software we've got.
Caleb Scoville: Microsoft word as a software they're coming together and and and and software speak web developer speak they call that shaking hands, so the two sophomores come together in order to do something like edit a document so that you don't have to download edit upload.
Caleb Scoville: All right, well, that is the end of the training what further questions do you have.
Caleb Scoville: Oh yeah yep so what you would do, and my vine sign in this i've got two.
Caleb Scoville: Instances two environments that I work in the one, and this one is not connected anymore, because this is my old one just why I use it for creating a lot of.
Caleb Scoville: stuff anyways so what you would do is you'd have this year if it's connected with mine sign drop down this little down carrot right here.
Caleb Scoville: And then you could just click on find sign right here, and that will take you into its own vine same page with this document, and then you could put in your fields.
Caleb Scoville: customize that page itself, and then it would take you to the next page where you're putting in all of the client slash whoever you're sending it to information.
Caleb Scoville: I could do a quick, if you want me to show you real quick I could open up.
Caleb Scoville: On the okay cool still.
Caleb Scoville: And then.
Caleb Scoville: I gotta go get my kids.
Caleb Scoville: boy turned on slow today.
Caleb Scoville: Oh um.
Caleb Scoville: that's a good question.
Caleb Scoville: Did you did you sign up for this like with an email Ricardo.
Caleb Scoville: Okay, then why don't you yeah actually post your put your email right into the chat right now.
Caleb Scoville: Oh okay that makes sense yeah the other two guys are are on there, but.
Caleb Scoville: Because they signed up through the.
Caleb Scoville: Through that site perfect.
Caleb Scoville: Do that wall.
Caleb Scoville: Do a bunch of things, while we're waiting for this to load.
Caleb Scoville: Yes, Alexander.
Caleb Scoville: Because I know that we can put I know that we can put let her head.
Caleb Scoville: and not let her head that's already like on the document itself but let her head, that is up there, and I also know that there is a way.
Caleb Scoville: But I don't know how to do it because, again i'm kind of like an elementary school substitute teacher teacher in this respect.
Caleb Scoville: Or, I know how it all works, I can teach you how to do it when it comes to like super technical stuff I just don't know because I don't do this I don't do it for anybody I just instruct it right.
Caleb Scoville: But um but there's ways to to create a letterhead and have it be dynamic so where on specific letterhead.
Caleb Scoville: says certain attorneys names and another lead letterhead it's got a very similar letterhead only the Attorney things are different, so there is a way to do that I don't know what that is.
Caleb Scoville: But I know for sure that in that way, there is a way to do that.
Caleb Scoville: Alright ricky Ricardo your.
Caleb Scoville: email us and there you have the word Doc and word and you had a picture in the header right yeah yeah so whatever you have on your original and this I mean my.
Caleb Scoville: My my logo is a I think it's either a jpeg or a PNG and so, if it's on the original document if it's in color it's going to come in.
Caleb Scoville: And it's going to come in that way yeah so with you, Alexander if we had like an image in there.
Caleb Scoville: My under my understanding is that there is a way to get that image on there without having to actually put it into.
Caleb Scoville: The.
Caleb Scoville: Like hard coded almost onto the document right.
Caleb Scoville: But again.
Caleb Scoville: I don't know how to do that all right don't get too excited about that because I don't know what the restrictions are and how that works.
Caleb Scoville: But I would definitely talk to your REP about that sin caleb told us that it was possible and and if the REP hasn't heard about it before they can chat with me and I can kind of fill them in on who who they should talk to internally.
Caleb Scoville: Okay awesome let's go into Anna Garcia Okay, so this was a fine sign that came back so it will appear in your feed and on the case itself from wherever it was sent out from but so since it's here let's just pretend like it's just any old document, not to find sign itself.
Caleb Scoville: drop that down.
Caleb Scoville: Find sign.
Caleb Scoville: let's try something else let's go into.
Caleb Scoville: yeah maybe it just wouldn't let me do that.
Caleb Scoville: You can do a word document or a PDF it will convert it into a PDF automatically if you are.
Caleb Scoville: If you do it from a word document.
Caleb Scoville: So you don't have to do anything as far as like you don't have to convert it beforehand.
Caleb Scoville: that's how fax works within file line as well.
Caleb Scoville: Goodness this is going slow.
Caleb Scoville: nope I don't want them.
Caleb Scoville: To click on that.
Caleb Scoville: ducks section so wherever you are whether it's in the Doc section or connected to that you will be able to find that file line drop down.
Caleb Scoville: And we'll wait, why would Oh, here we go.
Caleb Scoville: let's just say it's.
Caleb Scoville: Combined Doc and a Garcia versus Rachel john's this was a combined where we took a bunch of different files and combine them into one PDF just part of docs plus well select that.
Caleb Scoville: come up here to.
Caleb Scoville: My kebab menu.
Caleb Scoville: Find sign.
Caleb Scoville: That should.
Caleb Scoville: Come for you, it might make me sign in Oh, it did not so pretty basic two steps design and send designers where i'm putting those different fields on I can click put them in there drag and drop.
Caleb Scoville: Not gonna spend too much time there because it is relatively.
Caleb Scoville: Straightforward as far as how that goes.
Caleb Scoville: yep docs plus is a part of file finance part of that duck section we've got.
Caleb Scoville: we've got the Doc combine or beat stamper PDF editor ocr.
Caleb Scoville: To a folder sharing.
Caleb Scoville: And there's a fifth one oh importing of entire.
Caleb Scoville: folders.
Caleb Scoville: And it keeps its original folder structure.
Caleb Scoville: Alright, so awesome I put that in there we've got fields I can I can take um I can drag I can drop pop those in really just basic when they were, I think they were like hmm let's just not add any more color or anything more than we absolutely have to write.
Caleb Scoville: anyways So here we can put in the name of the file of the job I can associate it with either the case that i'm in or a different case.
Caleb Scoville: You create your own templates.
Caleb Scoville: yeah so you can create your own templates and, in fact, if I put this in here, so I can put in the contact here's the here's the information that I was telling you about email phone, etc.
Caleb Scoville: we've got a preview over here on the right, so you don't forget what it looks like.
Caleb Scoville: You can add more recipients, if you would like, you can have multiple signers this just sends the same thing to several people to be able to see it multiple signers gives us the ability to put in fields for several people at the same time.
Caleb Scoville: Signature settings could do it in black or blue depending on what your court wants right signature options we can upload or allow them to type message settings This is where we can configure specific text for text message and email that's been sent out.
Caleb Scoville: And then options, right here, this is how we can say all right, save this as a new template.
Caleb Scoville: And then we send a phone gets sent out signed once it's submitted it comes back you can see it on the case itself.
Caleb Scoville: In the activity feed right here, and then, if you're a follower on this case, then you would see that in your global feed as well if you're if you're a collaborator you're not going to see it on your global feed you just be able to see it when you come into the space.
Caleb Scoville: There you go all right, I gotta I gotta hop off Ricardo i'm going to send you that text or that email, and this goes for lance as well, but um if you have any further questions i'm happy to help or direct you to someone else who knows more technical stuff than I do.
Caleb Scoville: awesome alright guys have a great rest of your Friday have a great weekend don't do anything too crazy all right don't break the law, but you know, have a good one.
Caleb Scoville: See you guys later.